Ian Hundere

Atlanta, GA | (512) 410-0083 ian.hunde.re | github.com/ianhundere | linkedin.com/in/ianhundere | ian@hunde.re "perpetually taking an open book test while having fun"

Summary

As a passionate educator turned problem solver, I bring a unique perspective to my work in cloud infrastructure with years of experience working with developers, IaaS (AWS), and various data sources to create highly integrated solutions. Proficient in version control, tool selection, and pipeline building. Experience building personal full-stack and front-end apps using Node.js, React, Express.js, MongoDB, and Tone.js as well as an array of Bash/Python scripts. I also self-host a number of apps (Ninjam, Nextcloud, UniFi, etc) via a 5 node K3s cluster. My background in education has taught me the importance of clear communication and collaboration, and to continuously seek new challenges and opportunities to learn and grow.

Skills

AWS, Kubernetes, Terraform, Linux, Bash, Python, Docker, Ansible, Git, Packer, Vagrant, Datadog, New Relic, Zabbix, Sumo Logic, Prometheus, Grafana, Helm, Consul, Vault, Flux, Argo CD, GitHub Actions, Gitlab CI, CircleCI, PostgreSOL

Experience

DevOps Engineer II | Oddball | Atlanta, GA

April 2022 – Present

- Lead of the DevOps Community of Practice; facilitate discussions and presentations surrounding best practices and lessons learned as well as mentor junior engineers to improve technical growth and effectiveness
- Develop custom GitHub Actions; for instance, using Slack's Block Kit and Bash to detect Terraform drift providing detailed formatted alerts of potential creates, updates, and destroys of AWS GovCloud resources and others via Slack
- Apply log processing rules/regex to drop unwanted/noisy logs at the deployment level using podAnnotations, at the Datadog agent level using Helm (e.g. EKS) or using the Datadog configuration file (e.g. monolith environments)
- Create custom IAM permissions boundary to prevent privilege escalation and limit scope of IAM users and roles
- Resolve long running API routes (third-party external services) by rerouting via Nginx redirects to duplicated ASG and LB resources built using Terraform data sources triggered via CD pipelines; short-term fix
- Convert a variety of Jenkins jobs to GitHub Composite Actions
- Research and prepare the move of a Ruby based Sign-in Service controller from a monolith infrastructure to a
 microservice infrastructure to improve resiliency and availability

Cloud Infrastructure Engineer II | Revel Systems | Atlanta, GA

November 2020 – April 2022

- Lead effort to improve developer velocity by bundling monitoring with deployments (e.g. EKS, ECS, EC2, RDS etc.) through custom Terraform modules using the Datadog provider
- Rebuild GitLab Runner EKS cluster by improving its IaC, availability and disaster recovery through automation
- Develop modular CLI Bash script used by entire Infrastructure team to do a variety of tasks such as accessing RDS per PCI rqmts (e.g. IAM auth) with optional flags to list schemas, users, long running queries and pass valid SQL
- Build Ansible playbooks; for instance, to enable RDS IAM authentication and seed RDS instances with users/roles
- Separate Terraform from one to many repos by removing and importing resources from one tfstate file to another
- Increase developer velocity by assisting development teams with Terraform, GitLab CI/CD pipelines, AWS, *nix, containerization, etc. including creating tools (e.g. Terraform modules, CI/CD templates, scripts) for them to use
- Mentor junior engineers through regular check-ins, postmortems, and purposeful questions

DevOps Engineer | Artis Technologies, LLC | Atlanta, GA

February 2020 - November 2020

- Configure and maintain EKS clusters for multiple deployments
- Automate tasks with Bash scripts, Kubernetes Jobs, Kubernetes CronJobs, and AWS Lambda functions
- Install, configure, and maintain Sumo Logic, Datadog, CloudWatch, New Relic, and Falco to monitor site reliability, durability, integrity and confidentiality
- Implement CI/CD pipelines using CircleCI
- Performance tune pipelines to decrease deployment times by 60%
- Automate creation of security group rules to enable ingress connectivity from CircleCI runners to AWS resources
- Implement AWS WAF rules to protect against common web attacks; issues with the integration of Twilio as their IPs were also hosted on AWS, resulting in blocked traffic; custom WAF rules created to allow Twilio IPs

Software Engineer, DevOps & Training Platforms | Itential, LLC | Atlanta, GA

January 2019 – February 2020

- Configure and automate Itential's learning environment used by internal employees, external customers, and potential customers using Ansible and Docker
- Improve the launch time of lab containers by 30%
- Create RESTful APIs using Express and Puppeteer to automate CRUD operations (e.g. student enrollment/unenrollment; brittle, not a good idea)
- Deploy and configure openLDAP, Netbox, Zabbix and Grafana

Academic Technology Coach | Northside Independent School District | San Antonio, TX July 2016 – June 2018

- Create and teach a variety of professional development to improve teachers' instruction efficacy at 7 campuses
- Identify technology integration competencies among instructional staff in collaboration with administrators to deliver effective coaching to accelerate the professional growth of adult learners
- Make decisions related to instructional technology acquisition and deployment to encourage student engagement and academic rigor

Teacher, 4th and 5th grade | Pflugerville Independent School District | Austin, TX August 2013 – June 2016

- Utilize diverse teaching strategies to effectively address each student's learning style and ability
- Create and maintain training resources used to certify 3rd party clients
- Demonstrate a strong degree of teamwork ethic by assisting in the coordination of weekly staff meetings

Product Specialist Support | Apple Inc. | Austin, TX

September 2007 – August 2012

- Assist a number of companies (e.g. OfficeMax, Best Buy, etc.) with their support of Apple products
- Create and maintain training resources used to certify 3rd party clients
- Demonstrate a strong degree of teamwork ethic by assisting in the coordination of weekly staff meetings

Education

DigitalCrafts | Full-Stack Web Development | Atlanta, GA

Texas State University | Master in Education | San Marcos, TX

University of Victoria | B.A. in History | Victoria, B.C., Canada

September 2018 – January 2019 August 2010 – December 2012 September 2002 – August 2007